SRI SAINEE THIRUMURUGAN

DATA ANALYST

CONTACT ME AT

Unit 11/16 Courtney Street,North Melbourne,VIC,3051

srisainee2310@gmail.com

+61 413931624

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sri-saineethirumurugan/

https://github.com/littlebravesri

https://littlebravesri.github.io/

EDUCATION

Master of Data Science | RMIT University

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering | Anna University

SKILLS SUMMARY

- PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE
 - Python, R, Java
- Data Science Skills
 - Machine Learning, Deep Learning
 - Statistics
 - Data Wrangling
 - Data Mining
- Data Visualization Tool
 - PowerBI, Tableau
- Database Systems
 - MySql, SQLite, PostgreSQL
- Information Retrieval
 - Beautiful Soup, Scrapy
- Front End Technologies
 - HTML, CSS
- Back End Technologies/ Frameworks
 - Flask, Django REST framework
- Server
- Linux
- Web Services
 - Azure, REST framework
- Version control
 - o GitHub, Jira, Bitbucket

SOFT SKILLS

- Team Work through experience and projects.
- Ability to control a situation.
- Adaptable to change in work environment.
- Willing to learn.
- Can-do Attitude.
- Proactive.

REFERENCE

PERSONAL PROFILE

Master of Data Science graduate having well developed teamwork, communication and problem-solving skills broadened during academic experience. Possessing extensive knowledge in Python, R, SQL, PowerBI, Tableau and Azure through experience and projects. Confident about actively engaging in a dynamic and challenging environment to develop personal growth while contributing to the organization's success. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data and Analytics Officer

Dementia Australia (Contract) | Aug 2021 - Sept 2021 | Melbourne, Vic

- Verified the consistency of various forms in the website for marketing purpose.
- Identified different tags and triggers used in the forms via Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics to report of tracking activites such as link clicks and PDF downloads.
- Explored different marketing tools like MailChimp, Eventbrite, Formstack, Google Analytics to collect data for the purpose of visualisation.
- Used Zaiper to integrate the marketing tools to Google Sheets.
- Created zaps to automate the addition of new or updated data into Google Sheets.
- Imported the data from Google sheets into PowerBI and performed various visualisation as per the requirement of the marketing team.
- Documented the data preprocessing steps and data transformation perfomed in PowerBI.
- Delivered the visualisation with a story to the marketing team to understand the monthly performance
 of their marketing websites

Data Scientist

Sustainability Victoria (Capstone Project) | March 2021 - June 2021 | Melbourne, Vic

- Responsible for data collection of kurb side recycle materials of each Victorian council.
- Perfomed Data Preprocessing to clean the data sets.
- Designed various Machine Learning models such as Linear Regressions, Exponential Smoothing, XGBoost etc. to forecast future values of recycled materials.
- Designed Time Series models like ARIMA, FBprophet to predict future values of recycled materials.
- Assited in creating the dashboard in Python to visualise the results of the models.
- Documented the results of the models to compare and decide the best fit model for the data set.
- Worked in an Agile team environment.

Data Analyst

Wings Cyberspace International (Internship) | April 2021- July 2021 | Geelong, Vic

- Performed web scrapping on eBay using BeautifulSoup, Scrappy and ParseHub.
- Experimented Octoparse to perform web scrapping.
- Explored Elasticsearch an analytics engine.
- Automated the web scrapping program to scrape multiple depth levels within a page.
- Carried out Data Preprocessing to clean the scrapped data for visualisation.
- Designed dashboards using PowerBI and Tableau with data extracted from eBay.

Data Scientist

Know your terms (Volunteer) | November 2020 - January 2021 | Melbourne, Vic

- Extracted text from web pages using Beautiful Soup and Scrapy.
- Mined text from PDF and docx files for displaying relevant terms and conditions for the users.
- Worked in an Agile/Scrum environment.

Data Science and Analytics Intern

The Sparks Foundation (Internship) | October 2020 - October 2020 | Geelong, Vic

- $\bullet \quad \text{Developed dashboard using PowerBI to perform Exploratory Data Analysis.} \\$
- Performed Business Analysis using range of graphs and plots.
- Developed storyboard using Tableau to perform Time Series Analysis on COVID-19.
- Built interactive and animated visualizations to analyse the COVID data.
 Performed storytelling by interactive graphs enabling easy analysis.
- Code and snapshot of dashboard in https://github.com/littlebravesri/TheSparksFoundation